Hello, welcome to the next episode of German Literature in Hindi.
In the 42nd episode, we
learned a lot of grammatical concepts of German. Now in the next
3 episodes, we are going to see a survey structure of life
and we are also going to learn the tips which were
useful to me and my students. So,
I myself have
learned my German from where I went and
my students who have
given the exam and have also got good marks,
they all have to give WhatsApp,
so now whatever I will talk about will be
about relationships, but given in general
universal, it will be similar in other places also, baby,
in other exams also, okay,
and the second thing is that Baba, what is this
basic structure, the
structure of the exact structure and what is to be one
and what is the basic history picture, we have
seen them in our Examination Structural Tips episode 221.
If you have not seen it again, then
come and see it. You will have this basic science paper and
then the next one will
come to you easily, so from there we saw that there are
four parts, which are laser iron
scrubbing  Specially, there is a slight
difference here and in Jeevan Baba, all that was
passed together, here it is modular pass, which
means you will have to pass all four separately,
you will have to score minimum 60%, there is
another advantage of it as well, you can see these different modules and
their exams, okay, and first of all
understand what B1 is, so
after Jeevan, it has been clarified to you that if you
go anywhere in Germany or
in a German speaking country, you
can handle yourself, the return
instructions or if
something is playing on the loudspeaker somewhere, then you can understand
it and you can understand the basic
information and you can click on it, you can
talk on your thoughts, your simple topic, you
can share your experience simply, this is basically
notice also one and the exam pattern is
related to that, so basically
I have four parts in it, there is inspiration and
this ribbon, on that we are going to make a cigarette video
because its marking
system is a little different, it has  We will
make an accept video, lessner, this is a
tool like iron, it is in a basic format,
so today we will see both of them,
how are its formats and
what trick is required for it, we will see that let's
start from the very beginning, garlic
is a good total, so when you see this mask in the
answer sheet or in Nimar region, then by
multiplying it by 3.33
we will get the date of birth, but basically it is a
paper of thirty marks, you will see on the screen
that it has a total of five parts,
parlor and one daily, let me
explain that one two and final first second
third five, this is basically a
passage which we saw in and you have to write the answer on it,
which passenger, we will see later,
but basically very similar, so for a total of 6 marks, the
money for writing the answer below it,
number 3 is very interesting, you must have taken the
situation and
given 10 advertisements and you have to add
then match  Following this melodious, we will
see that there are details and the fourth one is
my favorite
that I will give you a theme and on that
people have written their opinion, you have to
say whether it is on the side of your skin or wrist or
not, it is very interesting, we
will see it in detail but the basic format is simple, so go and
see a handwritten form, the first
part is for general, personal matter,
that is mail, email or blog and on that
you can get six questions, you just have to
read that and answer those six questions,
here you have to write which one is right or wrong, e love station
for inch, so in
this platform dry, the second thing is very
important, can you even go to the seats, there will be
problem, Jio SIM, that means the
answer to the first question is already done, the answer to the last
question is done in the last, if you do
not have ID then that will also help you,
after that you have to read the first questions,
first if you read and
make notes, you can do it as you think, Bodi
Akbaruddin Owaisi, sometimes  It will not happen that the first
question is at the end and then the answer is
in the beginning, so the first six marks are very simple, there will be
a simple block time,
you have to write the answer on that, okay, the number of seconds is
also 282, there are two news,
so the news articles are small and on that
you have three questions,
ABC ones, okay, and the news articles are generally on
day-to-day life, that is,
rank in exchange for work, there will be any such topic
and you will have three questions on that for 3 minutes, like this, there will be two
six marks, it is simple, right, and the
shift, then it will generally be that you have
something, that is, if you have gone
to a fitness studio or a hospital, then the
inspection measures,
instructions for going to the swimming pool,
infection, or if you have brought a table to your home, then there will be
questions, so the general physician time,
because if you have to
go to the swimming pool inside, then go, the money is not our responsibility, if no
one says anything, then the rustproofing will proceed
This sequence is 6 416 marks,
understand it simple,
what happens in the third is that
you have new situations, that is, firstly,
you understand which job you will do, or you will
read books from a fan, such type
180 is religious and then there are people
and people also need some specific thing, for example, there is a band
called betel nut, that
means if there is a cream, that is,
I have to do jobs for holidays,
then along with that, French beans
ghee, and if there is a family, he has to do a job, he has to
learn computer with his husband, thirdly, there is someone
who can do job only on cricket,
fourthly, there is someone who
goes abroad to do a job, such prescription situations will be there
and then there will be 10 advertisements below,
one of them would have already gone for example, so
you have new advertisement, I will wait
in the attachment that I will
come to France for your work, second attachment will be
work in our hotel, you have to
pick up the quit, thirdly, there is computer
Learn and how to reduce it with it, so Unit-2
Just make sure what Arora Judgment is
saying about that Raksha Bandhan advertisement
and you have to add a little bit to it,
why what I did is that this is with
and this is a note and in that too none of these will
feel any product,
so you have to write this zero in front of it, so the prices
were separate, when you start them one by one,
you will understand, the phone is my
most favorite, what happens in it is that
you are given this cream, it means what does it mean
that that single shot late also, now sister
video or there should be a limit directly on auto bid
highway,
what should be given by sister and toxins
state on city center, there will be 300 such people and the
people gave their answer degree on it, sir later to the
editor's carrier, so in that the
person with me, is he from the team's side
or against it, a new one, so this is not to be done,
very simple, so support, if the theme is
that Baba should ban video games  Should it be or
not, then the first person will say, hey friend, I
absolutely believe that video games should be banned
because of that, the new generation gets very
dirty, unwanted children,
he must have written 5 sentences, so what should you do,
yes, this is from his side, or the other person will
say that it is the same, I
think that this will be of some benefit, till
date there is so much violence in films too, whoever wants to
watch it will check his
balance, then what will he get by banking, then
you will say no, most of the times in the
district road, you will have 4-5 sentences, in which
you had to remove two important sentences, in that
he will
say that I believe that this does
not make a soldier, or it will be
mixed sense such words sometimes, like it happens
in normal night also, anyone will put
yes, it is all right that there are boys in it,
that is all right, but what can be done that
whoever wants to do what, then I
feel that it should not happen, then for the
second finger one will have to be a businessman, in that was
interesting  It's something
where you can apply your mind,
it's just understand, there is
no way to write soft and easy, there are trees with
which you have to understand, so see, as I said, you
here Ghanshyam, what was for March 16, that
below Baba 65, we search for 7 routes,
messenger following for 7 minutes or
not, okay, so now let's see what can you do for this,
what are the tips of Dabangg, so first of all,
before the exam, we have to
increase our skills, the better it is,
Ram the best wishes, okay, to be for delivery, at
this time, you have no such thing that
if you search on the net, you will
get quality vocabulary, from there you can
increase your skills, read as much as you
can, whenever you can, you can study here, you will
get a lot of material,
you will get a lot of material on the website, the more
you get used to it, the better it is,
notice that you will also get two papers on the website,
you can solve them, also if
you want, I generally do
not do two at this time, but made  Hair fall
is like a book and I will not keep more than
10 or 12, you have to do this point, I have this
note, let's jump, understand the pattern,
after that you can do your pump silk,
what is your agility, how much is your vocabulary,
what can you do during the exam, so during this the
most
important thing you have 65
minutes and this is per minute
with your hands, you have 65
minutes and almost 15 words, Harman
you will not be able to understand, some words will
also be of care level etc. what you need to understand, you should
take out such a correct, every
advertisement, if you make a habit of reading correctly then it will
not happen, you need to find out
what is said in it,
go to the front and do this, what is in it, if you
take out then it will be work, understand, time
management is clear, secondly you have to
decide which zodiac name you want to go by, I
like myself and I
tell my students to do the
first three and four years,
you have to do the same, till now  It is important to have a fresh mind if there is
no time pressure and at the same time
sleep on the route, so if you are doing it properly, it is
really helpful, then first
solve the questions which are there in the match or not,
after that you can solve 125 questions in whatever order you have to
solve them, one very
important thing you have to remember is that
you have to
transfer the answers to the answer sheet in that 50 minutes, sometimes
what happens is that in the beginning
you can write your question on the paper,
but let's say when we are coming to the exam, it happens that
I also have to correct the paper and
transfer the answers inside neutrally, Chandan, you
can make a mistake, but still if that
request comes, then it is okay,
forward the question once and the most important thing is to
keep that 2-5 minutes, to transfer your
answers properly to the answer sheet,
you will have to be spirited
that if your German is good then you do
not need to do much, idea,
come to this Baba, have a clear thought  Keep in mind that
you have to fold it and take care of the time,
we are going now,
this viral is a very interesting thing, I
like it myself very much, so
if you see the challenge, after China, most
people fail somewhere,
if people get scared then it is because of the color, that is,
in that President's travel, still you
can go after being fully prepared, here it is a game of that minute, so it is
most important for you to remain calm there, so first of all we have to
see its pattern, be it send or send, the
pattern is always similar, something will be told, you have to
write the answer, if there are some
changes then we will also see those
details, the first tile is very
simple, what will happen in it, you will be told a total of five
texts, those five texts will be here, that is,
on your telephone's answering machine
or your announcement will be made
at the train station, that
Maulvi and every minute on every five
tracks there will be a write from your luck
response and an ABC question,
okay and you have to write its answer  So for
example, I will tell you one option
that you say hello, I am Doctor Marking
speaking from here and
we have to postpone your appointment today
till tomorrow, there is no doctor and you do
not need to bring any money from you,
you forgot your career type here last time,
remember that you have to take that on
this day, something not diet, you should hear it
or listen to it twice, see the advantage and then
you will get a question below that Baba, first of all, is that
your fit
appointment has been scheduled in front friends, someone is
ready and second thing, what do you have to take back, like this, turn on the
number two C car,
very simple, now see, why is there an easier time in a very date, first of all
you will hear this twice, okay,
second thing is that you will get a
small tractor, so you
can focus on that, third important thing,
before every tax, you will get 10 seconds,
in that 10 seconds at least read the question so that
you know what you have to hear
and once and before when  If you are listening,
then understand what is going on and you
can connect it to the other part. The second
time is interesting. What
happens in this is that you generally have a tour of a museum
or on the first day of your school
or if there is a support
program, then its schedule is told
and a person keeps doing a monologue. Now
you have to answer five questions on it. So the
most important
thing in this is that the text keeps playing and
you keep getting questions. So
what is the important thing, if you do
not understand one question, then do not worry,
stay with it. If you add on it, then the rest
of the questions will also remain. This is the
biggest mistake people make. Don't know, if you did not understand the question,
leave it. You will understand it later.
How will I do it? You will hear it only once. This important thing will be
heard only once, but the good thing is that
before that happens, you will get eight seconds. Use those eight
seconds very well.
Whatever you have, at least use that question.  If I
like it below then you will know that
first what are you expecting, if
possible then understand the answer also, but by entering
below at least five questions, this f5
is the third time, it is also similar that a
discussion will continue and there are seven questions on it,
but in this the
phone number of 2 native people's mother tongue is
German, they will keep talking,
normal conversation with others and it will continue and
you have 7 questions, there is a little restriction for this
because Rishi has to pause,
come on Prem thing it is important that if you do
n't understand a particular question then it will be fine,
all the questions, all the words will
not be understood, don't worry, if you don't understand then move
ahead and see the next question, made this very very important, otherwise what would have happened,
people would have left the police action, if
one did not come then we will see later, next is
definitely simple, a conversation will continue and there will be seven questions on it, the question right
or wrong  If we want to write, then
when this is finished, for us,
our fourth channel will be on the first one and when the fourth channel
comes, then confidence is the best award, this
voice is our
mark, so what happens in it, look, there was a
discussion, there is a moderator and two people are
happy, there is a
side for one thing, there is a side against something, for example, if the
children, that is, kindergarten, should be
sent to the depot, otherwise, one
person speaks from one side, this person
speaks from the other side and what you have to do is there are
statements below, out of which who
said bowling water, he said to follow this,
that person said no, you have to click, it is
very simple and here there are many
things for you which are on your side, one
you get a shoulder from the side to read, what is this,
other things are
told twice, they are told twice, so in that you can
easily cut, in the first thing, you can change
where they are playing and
in the second you can cut,
A plus York, there is a little thing which can
help you, first thing means that 3
people  Out of that, generally there is one man and two ladies,
that is in this condition, so
you will come to know about the second one. Today again
you can remember the difference in the voice of the people,
secondly I do not rest much
but you can understand logically also, if
someone said that keeping the same children
in kindergarten is against them, then
generally the one who is against said it is unreasonable,
I am not saying further how is this a
logical speech, but this is your lip mark, it can
help you, the other side will be told twice
and you just have to match the sentence, it is very very easy,
it is your lip mark, it is
important that then something happens, what is general,
second, it gets resolved little by little, that is why
people get a little tensed and then
fourth, I have to score, they forget,
some things are easy to understand, now let's see a few tips,
so the first tip is that
what can you do before your exam,
listen as much as you can, listen to
most of the people who say it to me, I
studied German for six months and one year but still
I do not understand any description, that is what you said Sureen  That's
important hard work I
always say in my lectures because no matter how much
cricket you play, a fakir won't
come, then why do you have to learn scientists, so
we're sadly challenging listening practice,
listen to whatever you want, listen to the cartoon in German, but
when you're going to give the exam,
your ears should be used to listening to German,
Dalit woman, there's
no need to do much, another paper, as I
said, will be available on the website, if you solve it, it
's just redmi, there's no need to use it to understand,
generally, the garlic that you're
making is the best,
if you've prepared for your writing, then it's
okay for pure run, hey
Pappu, there's no need to do much,
practicing puberty is important, the
most important thing is that during his off
because that's the game of that time, so the most
important thing is the Shastra is going simple,
so don't do much, it's going to be removed,
so don't get angry, there's one
question, there's time, especially in the second and
third attempt, if you didn't get one question, there are two
questions, leave it, we'll look at the rest  We
want 18 out of 30 rate Do
n't act like I haven't solved the entire city
Stay with that darkness Run with that conversion
care convert cycle option Next
these first and fourth are your scoring points Take
advantage of that If the house is narrated again then
listen to it calmly both times Don't leave the character like that in the first time
Listen to it calmly Secondly, if
you get 10 seconds Take advantage of that It is
possible to have passion Before listening at least
read the question It is very
beneficial Tune in to where you want to
which friend Sent it is simple
And look I myself
like individuals Because iodine sir
Challenge 4u The game there is bad You will enjoy the young man So it will always be at Do it
well
If you get tensed as to how it will happen Then there will be
tension on the contrary Club President So enjoy
this Orange said and it will
not remain in the basic format and it will just be like that the
same train number 17 in
place of platform number 18  19 is coming and
when I was taking the seats, I was forced to practice when the mind
stops working and when the mind
starts working, Dashrath, this
changes the vocabulary, so don't worry, practice as much as you can beforehand,
if you can understand the normal cartoons that are going on, if you can
understand the normal cartoons that are going on today, if you see the
normal ones
in the news channels, Deutsche Welle etc., they are
definitely small because tomorrow you can understand everything,
so you don't need to do much different,
urine is that very simple, okay, it is
important to remain calm at that time, one
question at a time for staff and till there is
scoring and tiles, focus on them
and in the second and third, don't you sir, don't know the
way, I hope
you have understood both writing and urine properly,
we will see you in the next episode,
we will meet in the next episode,
thank you.